<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ucas on (Quantitative) models and (klein) bottles</title>
    <link>http://hanveiga.github.io/tags/ucas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ucas on (Quantitative) models and (klein) bottles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 09:53:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://hanveiga.github.io/tags/ucas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fazer a Licenciatura em Inglaterra - Candidatura</title>
      <link>http://hanveiga.github.io/post/130617-0953_fazer-a-licenciatura-em-inglaterra--candidatura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 09:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hanveiga.github.io/post/130617-0953_fazer-a-licenciatura-em-inglaterra--candidatura/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Olá! Suponho que estejas agora no ensino secundário e estás a pensar em estudar no estrangeiro, em particular, em Inglaterra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ao contrário do sistema de acesso ao ensino superior Português, a candidatura em Inglaterra é um bocado mais longa, mas não tenhas medo, estás no sítio correcto para obter mais informação!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primeiramente, deves começar a preparar a candidatura um ano antes de começares na universidade (Setembro/Outubro). Não te preocures, não vais passar um ano inteiro a preparar a candidatura mas há documentos e talvez testes que tens que fazer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Há 3 etapas essenciais até à tua entrada para a universidade:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fazer e enviar a candidatura (de Outubro a Janeiro);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receber a(s) proposta(s) (desde a submissão da candidatura até Março);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receber a confirmação do teu lugar pela universidade (pode demorar até Agosto).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-fazer-a-candidatura:5fbbfba582625382ea3a20e0e4701a38&#34;&gt;1. Fazer a candidatura&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esta é feita através do &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ucas.com/apply&#34;&gt;http://www.ucas.com/apply&lt;/a&gt;. Aqui crias a tua conta que está associada à tua candidatura, vai ser aqui também que vais receber as propostas das universidades. Depois de registares, podes escolher os cursos e as universidades que te interessam (até 5)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i302.photobucket.com/albums/nn115/serverrestricted/ucas_zps1cdcb0db.png&#34; alt=&#34;O UCAS não vai gostar da minha contra troll...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vais precisar de várias coisas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal statement (Carta de motivação):&lt;/strong&gt; É aqui que tu podes personalizar a tua candidatura. Porque é que queres tirar este curso? O que é que te faz especial, interessante ou um bom candidato ao curso? Fala dos teus interesses, hobbies, prémios, etc, mesmo que não sejam completamente relacionados com o teu curso!
E mais uma coisa: relê o teu texto. Se não estás muito confortável com o Inglês, pede ajuda ao teu professor ou a alguém que seja fluente para te ajudar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference (Referência):&lt;/strong&gt; Isto é normalmente escrito por um professor, director de turma (ou director da escola), alguém que te conheça bem. Na minha opinião, deve falar das tuas competências, especificamente, não só como és um excelente candidato ao curso mas também uma pessoa interessante, ambiciosa, etc&amp;hellip;! Isto tem de ser escrito em Inglês, por isso, não deixes isto para a última da hora, fala com a tua referência com antecedência!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic/Employment Records&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Tests]:&lt;/strong&gt; Isto não é compulsório mas normalmente as universidades pedem um teste de inglês, geralmente o TOEFL ou o IELTS. Pode demorar um bocado para marcar o teste, fazê-lo e receber os resultados, por isso, dá uma vista de olhos para saberes quais centros é que oferecem estes testes com antecedência.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah! Repara que a tua candidatura vai ser enviada para todas as universidades a que te candidatas, por isso, evita mencionar nomes de universidades (ou coisas muito específicas sobre uma universidade) na tua carta de motivação/referência!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew! Já reuniste todos os materiais e enviaste a candidatura muito antes do prazo de entrega (mas não te preocupes se foi mesmo em cima da hora, eu enviei a minha 20 minutos antes do último dia!). Boa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##2. Propostas##
A partir do momento em que entregas a candidatura até Março, deverás receber respostas das universidades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uma das duas coisas podem acontecer: Ou recebes uma proposta ou uma rejeição. Se recebeste uma rejeição, não te preocupes, as universidades têm critérios diferentes, por isso, isto não quer dizer que as outras te vão rejeitar também. (Eu recebi 2 rejeições antes de receber qualquer proposta!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sejamos positivos! Recebeste uma proposta. Existem dois tipos de propostas, a proposta sem condições (unconditional) ou a proposta com condições (conditional offer). Geralmente, se ainda não terminaste o ensino secundário, receberás uma oferta condicional que pede por notas em certas disciplinas (por exemplo, eu candidatei-me a Matemática, por isso, tinha uma condição na minha nota em Matemática), talvez um teste de inglês, ou a média do secundário.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Já que me perguntaram, no meu caso, as propostas que recebi foram:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imperial College London, para Licenciatura em Matemática Pura: 19 a Matemática, 18 a Biologia e 18 a Física, 19 na média do secundário e &lt;sup&gt;110&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;120&lt;/sub&gt; no TOEFL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universidade de Edinburgo, para Licenciatura em Matemática Pura: 19 a Matemática, 18 na média do secundário e (aproximadamente&amp;hellip;) &lt;sup&gt;100&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;120&lt;/sub&gt; no TOEFL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universidade de Edinburgo, para Licenciatura em Matemática e Inteligência Artificial: 19 a Matemática, 18 na média do secundário e (aproximadamente&amp;hellip;) &lt;sup&gt;100&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;120&lt;/sub&gt; no TOEFL]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depois de receberes a(s) tua(s) proposta(s), tens que decidir quais é que te interessam. Só podes aceitar duas propostas, uma que vai ser a tua primeira escolha (Firm choice) e outra a tua segunda escolha (Insurance). Basicamente, o que acontece é que se não conseguires as notas que te pedem na tua primeira escolha, ainda tens a opção de ir para a segunda. Claro, isto só faz sentido se na tua primeira escolha tens uma proposta condicional!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##3. Confirmação##
Okay, agora terminaste o secundário e já tens as tuas notas. Deves contactar a universidade para confirmar o teu lugar e brevemente, o estado da tua candidatura no UCAS deverá dizer &amp;ldquo;Accepted&amp;rdquo;! Boa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se por alguma razão não conseguiste cumprir os termos da tua proposta, deves contactar a universidade a que te candidataste e explicar porque é que não conseguiste. Muitas vezes a universidade ainda aceita o candidato, mesmo que este não tenha cumprido todas as condições da proposta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bem, espero que isto tenha sido útil e boa sorte para as candidaturas! Há uns sites que me ajudaram bastante:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thestudentroom.co.uk&#34;&gt;http://www.thestudentroom.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ucas.com&#34;&gt;http://www.ucas.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishcouncil.org&#34;&gt;http://www.britishcouncil.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E os sites das universidades que te interessam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boa sorte e se tiveres perguntas, podes enviar-me um email em han.veiga@gmail.com!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Sobre mim:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Eu fiz o secundário na Escola Secundária Miguel Torga em Monte Abrãao. No meu último ano, enviei a minha candidatura através do UCAS para várias universidades. Acabei por ir para o Imperial College London, onde fiz a Licenciatura em Matemática e agora estou em Zurique a fazer um mestrado.&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying to undergraduate degree in the UK</title>
      <link>http://hanveiga.github.io/post/130617-0828_applying-to-undergraduate-degree-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 08:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hanveiga.github.io/post/130617-0828_applying-to-undergraduate-degree-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hello! So I guess you are now in high school and you are thinking about the idea of studying abroad, in particular, the UK. For some, this procedure might sound a bit daunting and complicated, but fear not because, you came to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast with the university system in Portugal (and a lot of places in Continental Europe), the application to University in the UK is different and requires a little bit of planning ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would suggest you to start gathering your application material roughly one year before the year you are suppose to start at university, so September/October. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry! It&amp;rsquo;s not like you will spend a lot of time on the application, but it&amp;rsquo;s better to have enough time to have a solid application before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance to university has essentially three stages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You make an application (from October till January);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You receive offer(s) (anytime from the day you apply till March);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You fulfill the offer and get the confirmation of admittance to university (this can take up to August).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-making-the-application:0e86272e9626bbab6be7328e18833205&#34;&gt;1. Making the application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is done through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ucas.com/apply&#34;&gt;http://www.ucas.com/apply&lt;/a&gt;. In here, you create an account for your application and it&amp;rsquo;s also here where you will get offers from different universities. So after you register, you can choose the degree(s) and universities you want to apply to, 5 in total, so choose wisely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need several things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal statement:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where you can personalise your application. Why do you want to study this degree? What makes you interesting, special or simply a good fit? Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to mention your passions, interests, accomplishments (in or outside the field you are applying to). Also, why do you want to go to England? Last piece of advice: &lt;em&gt;Proof read, proof read and proof read.&lt;/em&gt; If you aren&amp;rsquo;t too comfortable in English, ask your English professor for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference:&lt;/strong&gt; This is usually written by a professor/director of school. I would say it should be focused in why you are a good candidate and what have you accomplished until now. This should be written in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic/Employment Records&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Tests]:&lt;/strong&gt; Although this is not compulsory, odds are you will be asked, in your offer, to do an English test if you aren&amp;rsquo;t a native English speaker. Normally, it&amp;rsquo;s either TOEFL or IELTS. It can take a while to get these tests booked (and their results) so if you are 100% sure you want to go to England, you should take them anytime before (up to 2 years prior to the application&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that you only submit one application for all the places and degrees you are applying to, so, for instance, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mention why you want to go to X, Y, Z university because the others will read that too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, phew! Well done, so now you submitted your application&amp;hellip; Hopefully well in advance from the deadline (Although, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I submitted mine 20 minutes before the deadline&amp;hellip;) What now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##2. Offers##
So anytime from the date you applied to till March (if there&amp;rsquo;s no word until mid-march, you will probably get automatically rejected), you should receive updates on your application.
So two things can happen: You either get an offer or you get rejected. If the latter happens, don&amp;rsquo;t get dishearten, admissions can be strange, and one rejection from one institution doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you won&amp;rsquo;t get offers from others. (I actually got two rejections before I got offers.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s be positive! So now you received an offer. Again, two things can happen. You either get an unconditional offer (You are in! congratulations!) or a conditional offer. The idea is, if you still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished finish High School (or lack some tests, e.g: the English test), the universities want to make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t just relax with the offer and stop working, so they will ask you for certain grades (for instance, I applied for Mathematics, so I needed a good grade in Maths.), or an overall average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after you get your offers, you have to decide which ones to take. You can only have two offers, one being your &lt;em&gt;Firm choice&lt;/em&gt;
and one being your &lt;em&gt;Insurance choice&lt;/em&gt; - the latter means that if for some reason, you don&amp;rsquo;t make the grades on your Firm choice, you can still go to your second choice. Obviously, this only makes sense if you put a Conditional Offer as your Firm Choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##3. Confirmation##
So now, let&amp;rsquo;s fast forward again. You finished high school and got the grades, you should contact the university to confirm your place and your application status on UCAS should update! Well done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you for some reason didn&amp;rsquo;t make your grades, you should still contact the university you applied for and explain you situation. It can be that they will still accept you even if you missed your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, anyway, this is a long entry! Some places where you can get some good information are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thestudentroom.co.uk&#34;&gt;http://www.thestudentroom.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ucas.com&#34;&gt;http://www.ucas.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishcouncil.org&#34;&gt;http://www.britishcouncil.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the universities you are applying for websites!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck and if you have any questions, feel free to email me on han.veiga@gmail.com!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;About me:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I did my high school in a public school in Sintra, Portugal. During my final year I submitted my application through UCAS applying to several universities. I ended up in Imperial College London, where I graduated from a 3 year degree in Mathematics. I am currently doing my masters in Zurich.&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>